expertscolumn.com 2010-05-22

# Privacy Policy

1\. General: We are committed to protecting your privacy and we take our responsibilities regarding the security of information you provide to us very seriously. The purpose of this privacy policy is to inform you, as a visitor of this Website, what kinds of information we may gather about you when you visit the Website, how we may use that information, whether we disclose it to anyone, the choices you have regarding our use of that information and how you can correct that information. If you have any concerns, questions or comments about this privacy policy or the Website you can contact us by following the instructions set out in paragraph 12 of this privacy policy.

2\. Use of Information: In order to make use of certain services provided through the Website such as the forums, blogs, email newsletters, competitions and polls, you will need to register an account with us. When you do so, you will provide us with information about yourself and you will be able to select how we use your information for marketing purposes. You can update your marketing preferences at any time by following the instructions to amend your details in the account registration section. We will only use your information in accordance with your instructions and as set out in this privacy policy.

If you ask us to provide goods or services to you, we will use your information to provide those goods or services to you and to monitor our provision of those goods or services. We may also share your information with associated companies for marketing purposes. We or associated companies may contact you by mail, telephone, fax, email or by other electronic means with offers of goods and services or information that may be of interest to you. By providing us with your fax number, telephone numbers or email address you consent to being contacted by these methods for these purposes. If you do not want to receive marketing information from us or associated companies you can notify us of this as part of the registration process. Don’t worry – we won’t bombard you with lots of irrelevant information. You can stop receiving this information at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions on the correspondence you receive, by amending your marketing preferences, or by emailing [webmaster@expertscolumn.com](mailto:webmaster@expertscolumn.com), giving your email address and details of the information you no longer wish to receive.

By providing us with your personal information, you consent to us processing your information as set out in this privacy policy, to our processing your sensitive personal data, such as health data and you also consent to our transferring your information to countries or jurisdictions which do not provide the same level of data protection as the UK, if necessary for these purposes. If we do make such a transfer, we will, if appropriate, put a contract in place to ensure that your information is protected.

If you wish to take part in any poll or survey run through the Website, we will also use your information for the purposes specified in the poll or survey. We may also disclose non-personal, aggregated information we collect through the poll or survey to third parties.

If you wish to take part in any promotion or competition run through the Website, we will also use your information for the purposes specified in the promotion or competition, to make sure you are eligible to enter the promotion or competition, to contact you if you have won a prize and for publicity purposes.

3\. Disclosure to third parties: We will only pass your information on to associated third parties for the purpose of enabling them to send you information which may be of interest to you if you have indicated you are happy for us to do so in your marketing preferences. Don’t worry – we only ever pass on your contact details to third parties with your permission.

If any third party is organising and/or managing any promotion, competition, survey or poll run through the Website on our behalf, we may disclose your information to that third party to enable them to do so but they will be prohibited from using your information for any other purpose, unless you have given them specific consent.

Please note that if you upload or post any information to a public part of the Website, we may use it in accordance with our terms and conditions of use and it may be viewed and used by others.

4\. Maintenance and storage of information: Your information is collected and stored. We may keep your information for a reasonable period for the purposes set out in this privacy policy.

5\. Our email newsletters: If you subscribe to receive one or more of our email newsletters you will need to register an account with us. We will provide those newsletter(s) to you free of charge, unless otherwise stated.

Our newsletters may contain promotions or advertisements relating to goods or services provided by us or our group companies and associated third parties from time to time. If at any time you wish to unsubscribe from an email newsletter you may do so by following the unsubscribe instructions on the newsletter, on the Website, or by emailing [webmaster@expertscolumn.com](mailto:webmaster@expertscolumn.com), giving them your email address and details of the newsletter you no longer wish to receive.

6\. Published Information: Please be aware that when you post public information on or through the Website, that information can be accessed by the public and used to send you unsolicited communications. Expertscolumn accepts no responsibility for this.

7\. Third party sites: The Website contains links to third party websites. We may, on occasion, disclose non-personal aggregated information to the owners or providers of those third party websites. We link to a wide variety of other websites and we display advertisements from third parties on our Website. We are not responsible for the content or privacy policies of these websites or for third party advertisers, nor for the way in which information about their users is treated. In particular, unless expressly stated, we are not agents for those sites or advertisers nor are we authorised to make representations on their behalf.

8\. Cookies: The Website automatically gathers certain information such as IP addresses and the number and frequency of visitors to the Website and individual web pages. This is collected using cookies and is used by us, for security and monitoring purposes, to manage the Website, to track usage, to improve the Website and to ensure the Website is as appealing to visitors as possible. Cookies are pieces of information that are stored by the browser on the hard drive of your computer. The Website also uses cookies to enable us and any person who advertises on the Website to provide features such as remembering certain information about you and your preferences so that we and they can deliver targeted advertisements which will be of most interest to you. Cookies can be deleted from your hard drive or you can configure your web browser so that it rejects cookies. To learn more about cookies and how to reject them, visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "www.aboutcookies.org"). Rejection of cookies will not prevent you from using most of the features on the Website. If you experience any problems having deleted cookies, you should contact the supplier of your web browser.

We also include web beacons (also known as clear GIFs or web bugs) in our emails to track the success of our marketing campaigns. This means that if you open an email from us we can see which of the pages of our Website you have visited. Our web beacons do not store additional information on your computer but, by communicating with our cookies on your computer, they can tell us when you have opened our email. If you object to web beacons, we recommend that you follow the instructions for deleting existing cookies and disabling future cookies above. We will still know how many of our emails are opened and we will automatically receive your IP address, a unique identifier of your computer or other access device; but we will not identify you as an individual.

8.1. Advertisers Cookies and Web Beacons: Apart from us, our advertisers such as Google Adsense, Infolinks and other such advertisers can put cookies and web beacons on Website to collect information such as your ip address, browser information etc for their own purposes with which we have no association. 

8.2. DoubleClick DART Cookie:  
\-->Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site.  
\-->Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet.  
\--> Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL - <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html>

9\. Revenue Sharing: We use revenue sharing model to let our users make money from Adsense for their efforts. We split revenue into 70:30 ratio with 70% being given to authors and 30% being kept by us to manage all form of expenses and also to make some profit ourselves. We also let users take 5% additional on the earnings made by their referrers. 

10\. Security: In accordance with our requirements under the Data Protection Act 1998, we will adopt appropriate security procedures to help prevent unauthorised access to your information. We shall be not liable for any attempt to hack or crack or otherwise gain access to any part of this Website including any of your information.

11\. Usage of information: We may use your information as set out in this privacy policy and in any other manner you expressly consent to us doing so, we may also use your information for any purpose if we are required to do so by any law or other regulatory or government authority, to enforce the terms of use or to enforce our rights, or to protect the safety of others. In particular, we may collect and use personal information for the purposes of investigating and, if necessary, removing any content about which we receive a complaint.

12\. Policy changes: By using the Website you agree to the terms of this privacy policy and our terms of use. We may amend this privacy policy and the terms of use from time to time. If we do so, we will post an updated version on the Website. You will be bound by the new terms upon your continued use of the Website.

13\. Contact details: You are entitled to ask for a copy of the information we hold about you (for which we may charge a small fee) and to have any inaccuracies in your information corrected. If you have any general questions about the Website, you can contact us at [webmaster@expertscolumn.com](mailto:webmaster@expertscolumn.com) .
